ratemyarea.com 2010-01-04

# Privacy Policy | Rate My Area

We at RateMyArea.com care about your privacy and we respect your privacy rights. 

By using the Website and/or the RateMyArea Service, you permit the collection and use of your personal information as outlined below and you signify your agreement to this Privacy Policy ( **last updated on 30th September 2008** ). If you do not agree with these terms, you should not use the Website and/or a RateMyArea Service. 

### 1\. ABOUT OUR PRIVACY POLICY

**1.1** Our website **RATEMYAREA.COM** which includes any webpage containing this domain name, including any page that is enabled for use by a mobile device or any webpage redirected from another domain name (e.g. RATEMYAREA.CO.UK and RATEMYAREA.MOBI to this domain name) (the **"Website"** ) and the services provided on the Website (for a more complete description of the services see our Terms and Conditions) (the **"RateMyArea Service"** ) are operated by Locate Online Limited of Unit 9A, Nutgrove Enterprise Park, Nutgrove Way, Rathfarnham, Dublin 14, Ireland ( **"we"** , **"us"** and **"our"** ). The Website and the RateMyArea Service help people find and create local community and business information by soliciting and aggregating reviews. 

**1.2** This policy, our Terms and Conditions and any other documents referred to in either of them set out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. If you are a Business Member then the Additional Business Member Terms also form part of your agreement with us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. 

### 2\. HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION ON RATEMYAREA

**2.1** When registering as a user of the Website or during your time as a user of the Website you will be asked to provide information to us. We will inform you at the time of collecting information from you whether you must provide the information to use the Website or a particular RateMyArea Service, or whether the provision of information requested by us is optional. We will inform you at the time of collecting information from you whether the information that you provide to us will be accessible to other users of the Website or by third parties, so that you can decide whether to provide the information to us. 

**2.2** We may collect and process the following data about you: 

**2.2.1** if you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence; 

**2.2.2** information that you submit in response to surveys or polls; 

**2.2.3** details of transactions you carry out through the Website; 

**2.2.4** details of your visits to the Website including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access; 

**2.2.5** proof of identity that we request from you before we disclose personal information to you that we hold (in order to establish that we are disclosing the personal information to you and not to someone pretending to be you); and 

**2.2.6** personal details that you submit to us, such as your name, address, telephone number, email address, gender and date of birth. 

**2.3** When providing us with Content on the website it is your responsibility to ensure that your Content does not contain information which would identify any other living person including any information which might connect information to an identifiable person **unless** you have ensured that that: 

**2.3.1** you are entitled to provide us with the information relating to that individual; 

**2.3.2** the individual is agreeable to the use of their personal data in the manner set out in this agreement; and 

**2.3.3** you have brought this Privacy Policy and Website terms and conditions to their attention in advance of uploading the information. 

You should be particularly careful that you have complied with these obligations when uploading items such as photographs, user reviews and other specific information which might identify another living individual or which provides information connected to them. You are reminded that we have the right to amend, remove and/or anonymise any content which has been provided to us through the Website, including where it deals with another person’s personal data. If you have provided us with personal data regarding another person without their consent or knowledge you agree and acknowledge that we may provide your personal data to the person to identify the source of the information, and/or to the Data Protection Commissioner’s Office or other supervisory or regulatory authorities. 

### 3\. USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION

**3.1** The Website's users write reviews or comments about third party products, services, areas, local communities and businesses that they then post on the Website, or they award scores to third party services and products. These reviews, comments or scores can then be accessed and read by other users of the Website. You can search for registered users of the Website, whether they are individuals or groups. If you choose to be a registered user of the Website, we will display a limited amount of personal information about you, so that users are able to evaluate a particular review; you will be able to control the type of personal information about you which will be displayed in this way. 

**3.2** We use information held about you in the following ways: 

**3.2.1** to ensure that content from the Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer; 

**3.2.2** to provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes; 

**3.2.3** to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us; 

**3.2.4** to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so; 

**3.2.5** to notify you about changes to our service; and 

**3.2.6** to publically display a limited/controlled amount of personal information, so that users are able to evaluate a particular review 

**3.3** Information such as your username, photograph, street level location (e.g. Pembroke Park), personal profile, Website history profile, group memberships and any personally identifiable information you have included in your reviews, ratings and comments you publish may be shown to other users of the Website and the RateMyArea Service. The user of the Website's history profile consists of, for example, your date of joining, previous reviews, ratings, and other material which you have contributed and whether any other user has "high fived" you. Your personal profile would consist of, for example, your likes and dislikes. 

**3.4** We may sell or licence your reviews to third parties for their use (including for publishing) without remuneration to you, in which case your username/display name and any personally identifiable information you have included in your reviews may be shown to users/ readers of such third party media. Except as set out in this Privacy Policy, we do not sell, rent, share, trade or give away any of your personal information. 

**3.5** We may also use your email address to send you updates or news regarding the Website or a RateMyArea Service, but you may choose not to receive emails of this type by accessing the "My Account" page of the Website and updating your notification settings. Additionally, we use your email address to contact you on behalf of your friends and group contacts (such as when someone sends you a personal message). 

**3.6** We may use your reviews to personalise the Website and identify/feature popular members. For example, we may promote the most popular and latest reviews, groups, listings and members. We may also promote most active members. While we do not expect to transfer the complete review and member database to others, we use the database throughout our networks and to generate results for others. 

### 4\. DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION TO OTHER PEOPLE

**4.1** We do not disclose to any third party personal information that you provide to us unless we have your permission or we believe the law permits or requires it. 

**4.2** If you provide personal information to us you understand and agree that we may disclose your personal information to the following third parties: 

**4.2.1** if you have indicated at registration, or at any time during your time as a user of the Website, that you are happy to receive information or promotions from selected third parties about goods and services which may be of interest to you, you consent to us sending you such offers or information. You may opt out of receiving such offers or change your preferences at any time by accessing the "Email notifications" tab on the "My Account" page of the Website or alternatively, if you have problems doing this, you can contact us at [keepusbusy@ratemyarea.com](mailto:keepusbusy@ratemyarea.com); 

**4.2.2** any member of our group of companies, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries; 

**4.2.3** to the prospective seller or buyer of any business or assets related to the Website or all or part of Locate Online Limited; 

**4.2.4** to a third party if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data with that third party in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms and Conditions and other agreements, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Locate Online Limited, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with third parties for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

**4.3** We will notify you when information about you may be provided to third parties in ways other than explained above, and you will have the option to prevent such information sharing at the time that we notify you. 

**4.4** We do not disclose personal information about you to third parties (including advertisers or marketing companies), but we may provide them with aggregate anonymised information about the Website's users. For example, we may inform them that 500 men aged under 30 have clicked on their advertisement on any given day or we might inform third parties regarding the number of unique users who visit the Website, the demographic breakdown of our community users of the Website or the activities that visitors to the Website engage in while on the Website. We may also use such aggregate anonymised information to help advertisers reach you with more relevant information and to help them improve their service to you the kind of audience they want to target (for example, we may inform businesses that their target market is 20-35 year olds, residing in Dublin 8). We may make use of the personal data we have collected from you to enable us to comply with our advertisers' wishes by displaying their advertisement to that target audience but more importantly to help you receive more relevant information from businesses you might be interested in. 

**4.5** We may provide your personal data to third parties for purposes that you agree to elsewhere in this Privacy Policy where those third parties based outside of Ireland or outside the European Economic Area (which may not provide the same protection for such information as offered in Ireland), and you consent to a transfer of your personal information to third parties identified in this Privacy Policy for purposes identified in this Privacy Policy. 

### 5\. SECURITY AND CONTROL OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA

**5.1** We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

**5.2** Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of the Website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone. 

**5.3** Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to the best of our ability to prevent unauthorised access. **You acknowledge that we are not responsible for any intercepted information sent via the Internet, and you hereby release us from any and all claims arising out of or related to the use of intercepted information in any unauthorised manner.**

**5.4** You should be aware that when you voluntarily disclose personally identifiable information and agree to make that information public on the Website (e.g., user name, e-mail address) via reviews, messages, forums, postings or in other areas of the Website and/or RateMyArea Service, that information, along with any substantive information disclosed in your communication, can be collected, correlated and used by third parties. These third parties or other Website users may use your information to send you unsolicited messages if you make the information available publically or to them on the site. Such activities are beyond our control. Please do not post any personal information on the Website that you wish to keep private. 

**5.5** As a registered user of the Website and/or the RateMyArea Service, you can modify your personal information at any time by accessing the "My Account" section of the Website or alternatively if you have problems doing this, you can contact us at [keepusbusy@ratemyarea.com](mailto:keepusbusy@ratemyarea.com). It is your responsibility to keep your personal information up to date at all times. 

### 6\. LINKS TO THIRD PARTY WEBSITES

**6.1** The Website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates as well as third party websites to which we have no affiliation. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. 

### 7\. MOBILE SERVICES

The Website includes certain features that are available via your telephone and mobile phone/device. One of the features is called "Free Call". We do not charge for the "Free Call" RateMyArea Service. We provide the "Free Call" facility free of charge to both registered and unregistered users of the Website. This facility allows you to telephone, through the Website, a business appearing on the Website provided that you have provided your telephone/mobile number to us and you click on the "Free Call" button. "Send to Mobile" SMS and other mobile business information services are also available to registered users in a similar manner. You agree that we may communicate with you regarding the Website and the RateMyArea Service by any electronic means whatsoever to your telephone or mobile device and that certain information about your usage of the telephone and mobile service may be communicated to us. Please note that your telephone and/or mobile service provider may charge you to receive communications from us under your contract with them and you should check your arrangements with your telephone and/or mobile service provider with regards to such charges, but these are not charged by us. 

### 8\. IP ADDRESSES AND COOKIES

**8.1** We may collect information about your computer, including (where available) your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration, statistical purposes. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual. 

**8.2** For the same reason, we may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. On revisiting the Website our computer server will recognise the cookie, giving us information about your last visit. They help us to improve the Website and to deliver a better and more personalised service. They enable us: 

**8.2.1** to estimate our audience size and usage pattern; 

**8.2.2** to store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customise the Website according to your individual interests and make your usage of the Website more enjoyable; and 

**8.2.3** to speed up your searches. 

**8.3** You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of the Website. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to the Website. 

**8.4** For information on how to control your cookies go to [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

### 9\. ACCESS TO INFORMATION AND UPDATING, VERIFYING AND DELETING PERSONAL DATA

**9.1** At any time, you can make a written request to have access to all the personal information that we hold about you. We will provide this information to you and may request a small administrative charge. 

**9.2** You may inform us of any changes in your personal data and in accordance with our obligations to you, we will update or delete your personal data accordingly. 

### 10\. CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

Any changes we may make to our Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. You should visit this page periodically to review any changes to the Privacy Policy. 

### 11\. USER FEEDBACK AND COMPLAINTS

Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy are welcomed and should be addressed to [legal@ratemyarea.com](mailto:legal@ratemyarea.com). 

### Thank you for visiting RateMyArea.
